Alvin H. Clemens

I am a recent graduate of the University of Utah's coding bootcamp for Full Stack Web Development, with a Bachelor's Degree from Saint Michael's College in Political Science. These last few months have been exciting, working in react and furthering my understanding of the connections of the front end to the back end services. I am eager to keep learning and have proved to myself that no problem is too hard to solve.

E Palo Verde Way Cottonwood Heights, UT 84121 (610) 506-7532

Email: Alvinclemens@gmail.com

GitHub:

https://github.com/Cloggedbat

My Portfolio:

https://alvinajprofile.herokuapp.com/

PROJECTS

Sure-Vote

GitHub:https://github.com/jburz/sure-vote

LiveSite: https://young-journey-30565.herokuapp.com/

This app was built as my final project and was built to be a secure voting site. My job was to build our facial recognition lock to secure the site.

<u>Technologies</u>: React.js, JavaScript, Express.js, Passport.js, Nodemailer, Azure API, MongoDB

Remember Them

GitHub: https://github.com/Cloggedbat/remember-them LiveSite: https://protected-forest-25007.herokuapp.com/

Remember Them is a web-based application that is a tribute page to fallen U.S. service members. The user can research fallen heroes, add a hero to the database, link to other military-related websites, and discuss the fallen in the forum. They can also contact administrators to provide feedback.

<u>Technologies</u>:Dotenv, Express-Handlebars, Nodemailer, Nodemon, Sequelize, ES Lint

EXPERIENCE

Ski Butlers, Park City Utah — Team Lead

November 2019 - March 2020

Stowe Cider, Stowe Vermont — Head Sales Representative

February 2018 - June 2019

Managed a 13.5% growth in all cider sales in the New England and New York markets; opened new accounts in existing markets, helped in the production and packaging of thousands of gallons of cider

VPIRG (Vermont Public Interest Research Group), Montpelier Vermont — *Climate and Clean Energy Associate*

August 2017 - January 2018

Worked with advocates on informing the state population about uses of Volkswagen settlement funds; conducted research on Vermont enhanced town energy plans; educated citizens on the Essex Plan to reduce Vermont's carbon footprint

VPIRG, Burlington Vermont — *Director of Logistics Summer Canvas*

May 2016 - August 2018

Planned and organized trips for summer canvas; managed an office of 90 canvassers; organized all logistical needs for the day-to-day; self-fundraised over \$22,000 and helped reach team fundraising goals of over \$800,000.

SKILLS

9 months of Javascript experience, fundraising and sales skills,video editing, research, writing, presenting; teamwork, interpersonal/customer service skills, 12 years of ski racing and FIS experience

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Microsoft Azure, Adobe Photoshop, Filmora X

EDUCATION

University of Utah, Salt Lake City Utah — Full Stack Web Development Certificate

July 2020 - January 2021

Saint Michael's College, Colchester Vermont — Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

August 2013 - May 2017